Howells family. Howells family papers (MS Am 1784-1784.13): Guide.
Howells family papers,
- II. bMS Am 1784.4: Tributes to William Dean Howells on the occasion of his 80th birthday.
  - Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (39); (p.42)
  - Gildersleeve, Basil Lanneau, 1831-1924. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (40); (p.43)
  - Gillette, William, 1853-1937. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (41); (p.44)
  - Gilman, Lawrence, 1878-1939. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (42); (p.48-49)
  - Glasgow, Ellen, 1874-1945. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (43); (p.45)
  - Gosse, Sir Edmund, 1849-1928. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (44); (p.50)
  - Griffis, William Elliot, 1843-1928. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (45); (p.46)
  - Gummere, Francis Barton, 1855-1919. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (46); (p.47)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (47); (p.51)
  - Harben, William Nathaniel, 1858-1919. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (48); (p.52)
  - Hardy, Arthur Sherburne, 1847-1930. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (49); (p.53)
  - Hastings, Thomas, 1860-1929. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (50); (p.54)
  - Hibben, John Grier, 1861-1933. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (51); (p.55)
  - Hitchcock, Ripley, 1857-1918. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (52); (p.56)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (53); (p.57)
  - Hughes, Rupert, 1872-1956. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (54); (p.58)
  - Irwin, Wallace, 1876-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (55); (p.59)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1853-1937. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (56); (p.61)
  - Johnson, Rossiter, 1840-1931. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (57); (p.60)
  - King, Basil, 1859-1928. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (58); (p.62)
  - Lane, Franklin Knight, 1864-1921. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (59); (p.63)
  - Ledoux, Louis Vernon, 1880-1948. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (60); (p.64)
  - Lee, Tessa. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (61); (p.65)
  - Lefevre, Edwin, 1871-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (62); (p.66)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard, 1866-1947. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (63); (p.67-68)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (64); (p.69)
  - Long, John Cuthbert, 1892-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (65); (p.70)
  - Low, Will Hicok, 1853-1932. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (66); (p.71)
  - Lummis, Charles Fletcher, 1859-1928. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (67); (p.72)
  - McCracken, William Denison, 1864-1923. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (68); (p.79)
  - McCutcheon, George Barr, 1866-1928. 1 letter to the Joint Committee of the Literary Arts; 1917., (69); (p.78)
  - MacKaye, Percy, 1875-1956. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (70); (p.73)
  - Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (71); (p.74)
  - Marquis, Don, 1878-1937. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (72); (p.83)
  - Martin, Edward Sandford, 1856-1939. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (73); (p.75)
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1869-1950. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (74); (p.76)
  - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (75); (p.77)
  - Mitchell, Langdon Elwyn, 1862-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (76); (p.81-82)
  - Moffett, Cleveland, 1863-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (77); (p.84)
  - Morris, Harrison Smith, 1856-1948. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (78); (p.80)
  - Page, Thomas Nelson, 1853-1922. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (79); (p.93)
  - Page, Walter Hines, 1855-1918. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (80); (p.94)
  - Payne, William Morton, 1858-1919. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (81); (p.85)
  - Peattie, Elia (Wilkinson) 1862-. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (82); (p.86)
  - Peixotto, Ernest, 1869-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (83); (p.92)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (84); (p. 87)
  - Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (85); (p.95)
  - Poole, Ernest, 1880-1950. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (86); (p.88)
  - Pottle, Juliet Wilbor Tompkins. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (87); (p.91)
  - Putnam, George Haven, 1844-1930. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (88); (p.89)
  - Puzen, Will. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (89); (p.90)
  - Rhodes, James Ford, 1848-1927. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (90); (p.96)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, pres. U.S., 1858-1919. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (91); (p.97)
  - Ruckstuhl, F. Wellington. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (92); (p.98)
  - Schouler, James, 1839-1920. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (93); (p.99)
  - Sedgwick, Henry Dwight, 1861-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (94); (p.100)
  - Seton, Ernest Thompson, 1860-1946. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (95); (p. 104)
  - Shorey, Paul, 1857-1934. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (96); (p.103)
  - Simmons, Laura. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (97); (p.110-112)
  - Sloane, William Milligan, 1850-1928. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (98); (p.101)
  - Smedley, William Thomas, 1858-1920. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (99); (p.102)
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (100); (p.105-109)
  - Taft, Lorado, 1860-1936. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (101); (p.117)
  - Taylor, Henry Osborn, 1856-1941. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (102); (p.113)
  - Thayer, William Roscoe, 1859-1923. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (103); (p.114)
  - Ticknor, Caroline, 1866-1937. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (104); (p.115)
  - Trent, William Peterfield, 1862-1939. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (105); (p.116)
  - Warren, Whitney. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (106); (p.119)
  - Wells, Herbert George, 1866-1946. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (107); (p.130)
  - Wendell, Barrett, 1855-1921. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (108); (p.128)
  - White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (109); (p.120)
  - White, Stewart Edward, 1873-1946. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (110); (p.121)
  - White, William Hale, 1831-1913. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (111); (p.126)
  - Whitlock, Brand, 1869-1934. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (112); (p.131)
    Wilkinson, Florence. See Evans, Florence (Wilkinson).
  - Williams, Frances Howard, 1844-1922. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (113); (p.122)
  - Williams, Jesse Lynch, 1871-1929. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (114); (p.132)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, pres. U.S., 1856-1924. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (115); (p.123)
  - Woodbury, George Edward, 1855-1930. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (116); (p.129)
  - Wyatt, Edith Franklin, 1873-1958. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (117); (p.124-125)
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (118); (p.133-134)
- III. bMS Am 1784.5-1784.6: The Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells Collection
  - A. bMS Am 1784.5: Correspondence of Elinor Howells
    - 1. Letters to Elinor Howells (purchase)
      Letters to Elinor Howells from various correspondents.
      - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1836-1907. 1 letter; 1881., (1)
      - Alma-Tadema, Laura Theresa, lady, d. 1909. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (2)
      - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887. 2 letters; 1863., (3)
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910. 4 letters; 1880-1909 [n.d.]., (4)
      - Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1832-1907. 1 letter; 1880., (5)
      - Custer, Elizabeth (Bacon) 1842-1933. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (6)
      - Douglas, David, 1823-1916. 1 letter; 1909., (7)
      - Fothergill, Jessie, 1851-1891. 1 letter; 1883., (8)
      - Fuller, Agnes G. 1 letter; 1887., (9)
      - Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940. 1 letter; 1894., (10)
      - Harland, Henry, 1861-1905. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (11)
      - Harte, Bret, 1836-1902. 1 letter; 1871., (12)
      - Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, pres. U.S., 1822-1893. 1 letter; 1880., (13)
      - Howe, Julia (Ward) 1819-1910. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (14)
      - James, William, 1842-1910. 1 letter; 1890., (15)
      - Osgood, James Ripley, 1836-1892. 1 letter; 1866., (16)
        Also sent on behalf of James T. Fields.
      - Paget, Violet, 1856-1935. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (17)
      - Piatt, Sarah Morgan (Bryan) 1836-1919. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (18)
        Riggs, Kate Douglas (Smith) Wiggin, 1857-1923. See Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) 1857-1923.
      - Thaxter, Celia (Laighton) 1835-1894. 2 letters; 1876-1880., (19)
      - Vereshchagin, Vasilii Vasil'evich, 1842-1904. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (20)
      - Warner, Charles, Dudley, 1829-1900. 2 letters; 1879-1880., (20a)
      - Washington, Booker Taliaferro, 1856-1915. 1 letter; 1907., (21)
      - Whitney, Anne, 1821-1915. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (22)
      - Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) 1857-1923. 3 letters; [n.d.]., (23)
      - Wister, Sarah Butler, 1835-1908. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (24)
      - Woolson, Constance Fenimore, 1840-1894. 4 letters; 1882 [n.d.]., (25)
        Letter (4) is noted as being incomplete as of February 2002.
    - 2. Letters to Elinor Howells (gift)
      - Brunetta, Eugenio. 1 letter; 1867., (26)
        *45M-520
      - Clemens, Olivia (Langdon) d. 1904. 2 letters; [1876] [n.d.]., (27)
        *45M-521
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910. 1 letter; 1889., (28)
        With note to William Dean Howells and two typed copies.
        *45M-522
      - Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, pres. U.S., 1822-1893. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (29)
      - Harford, Oliver, 1863-1935. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (30)
      - James, Henry, 1843-1916. 6 letters; [1881]-1907 [n.d.]., (31)
        *45M-524
      - Thaxter, Celia (Laighton) 1835-1894. 1 letter; 1876., (32)
    - 3. Letters from Elinor Howells
      Letters from Elinor Howells to various correspondents.
      - Fréchette, Annie (Howells), addressee. 16 letters; 1863-[1895] [n.d.]., (33)
        No. 2 with letter from W.D. Howells to Annie (Howells) Fréchette.
        16: *54M-329
      - Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, pres. U.S., 1822-1893, addressee. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (34)
      - Howells, Aurelia H., addressee. 13 letters; 1863-[1871] [n.d.]., (35)
      - Howells, Eliza, addressee. 1 letter; 1864., (36)
      - Howells, Mary (Dean), addressee. 5 letters; 1864-1868 [n.d.]., (37)
        No. 1 with letter from W.D. Howells to Mary (Dean) Howells.
        No. 3 with note from W.D. Howells to Aurelia Howells.
      - Howells, Samuel Dean, addressee. 3 letters; 1864 [n.d.]., (38)
      - Howells, Victoria Mellor, addressee. 6 letters; 1863-1882 [n.d.]., (39)
      - Howells, William Cooper, 1807-1895, addressee. 15 letters; 1863-1883 [n.d.]., (40)
      - Przemeszl, [Miss ], addressee. 1 letter; 1865., (41)
        With typed transcript.
      - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902, addressee. 1 letter; [1885]., (42)
  - B. bMS Am 1784.6: Compositions and drawings by Elinor Howells
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Dinner cards, n.p., n.d.], (1); 1s.(2p.)
      Signed by Sarah Orne Jewett,; S.L. Clemens,; James R. Osgood and others.
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. A.MS. pocket diary and memorandum book. [v.p.] 4 Feb. 1863 - 8 Aug. 1869., (2); 138s.(138p.)
      With a typed transcript.
      *48M-30F
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Venetian diary]. A.MS. (unsigned); [v.p.] 13 Jun.[1863] - 22 Jun.[1865], (3); 1v.
      Includes some entries by W.D. Howells and drawings by Elinor Howells.
      *43M-798F
      TS: *59M-283
      TS: *43M-799F
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Drawing: Winnie, Pilla, and Johnny Howells]. Watercolor (unsigned); [n.p., 1 Mar. 1874], (4)
      Made for the 37th birthday of William Dean Howells.
      *56M-193F
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Drawings: Frontispiece and title-page for No love lost.] Pencil sketch (unsigned); [n.p., ca. 1869], (5)
      - Frontispiece
      - Title page, recto
      - Title page, verso
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Sketches: In Joe's greenhouse, (1861); The mulberries (ca. 1865); Mary as "La folie" (1865)], (6); 2s.(3p.)
      *45M-516
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Sketch: Giovanna, Winifred's Italian nurse. n.p., n.d.], (7); 1s.(1p.)
    - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910. [Watercolors: Venetian lady (Venice, 1865); Drawing from Elinor Howells' Venetian sketch book, n.p., Oct. 1866], (8); 2s.(2p.)
- IV. bMS Am 1784.7: The Winifred Howells Collection
  - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1836-1907. A.L.s. to Winifred [Howells]; 1885., (1)
    *43M-797F
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910.; [Mark Twain's adhesive scrap book] New York, [ca. 1873]., (2)a b
    With autograph inscription of Clemens to Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells, Hartford, 1877.
    Pasted in are clippings of poems by Winifred Howells.
    With poem by Antoine Leonard Achille Fréchette, "A Winifred Howells."
    *43M-787
  - Fields, Annie (Adams) 1834-1915. [Portrait: carte de visite photograph] Boston, [187-?], (3)
    Inscribed: Winifred Howells, with the love of Annie Fields.
    *43M-794F
  - Howells, Winifred, 1864-1889. A day in the life of a certain little girl. A.MS., [n.p., ca. 1878], (4); 8s.(9p.)
    A verse with silhouette illustrations by Mildred Howells.
    *43M-791F
  - Howells, Winifred, 1864-1889. [Autograph album]. MS.s.; [v.p., 1876-1888], (5)a b; 1v. 1 folder
    Contains original and unpublished poems, inscriptions, etc. by T.B. Aldrich,; Sarah Orne Jewett,; S.L. Clemens,; H.W. Longfellow,; Edmund Gosse,; O.W. Holmes and others.
    *43M-790F
  - Howells, Winifred, 1864-1889. [Portrait: carte de visite photograph] Boston, [n.d.]., (6)
    *43M-795F
  - Premio-Real, José Antonio de Lavalle y Romero, conde de. [Portrait: carte de visite photograph] [n.p., ca. 1877]., (7)
    Inscribed: To Miss Winifred Howells by Premio-Real, Quebec, 12 May 1877.
    *43M-792F
  - Thaxter, Celia (Laighton) 1835-1894. 1 letter to Winifred Howells; 1875., (8)
  - Winifred Howells while living in Cambridge about 1871: carte-de-visite photograph; Boston, ca. 1871., (8a)
    A. Marshall (Boston), photographer.
    *43M-795F. Gift of Mildred and J. R. Howells; received: 1944 May 29. [Found with: MS Storage 281. Collection materials assembled by Carolyn Jakeman].
  - Winifred Howells: carte-de-visite photograph; Quebec, ca. 1872., (8b)
    Taken in Quebec the winter she spent with her grandfathr at the consulate there.
    Livernois (Quebec), photographer.
- V. bMS Am 1784.8-1784.10: The Mildred Howells Collection
  - A. bMS Am 1784.8: Correspondence of Mildred Howells
    - 1. Letters to Mildred Howells (purchase)
      Letters to Mildred Howells from various correspondents.
      - Aldrich, Lilian (Woodman) d. 1927. 1 letter; 1920., (1)
      - American academy of arts and letters. 1 letter; 1921., (2)
        A printed invitation.
      - Ames, Fanny B. 1 letter; 1928., (3)
      - Bacheller, Irving, 1859-1950. 1 letter; 1920., (4)
      - Beer, Thomas, 1889-1940. 1 letter; 1924., (5)
      - Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931. 1 letter; 1921., (6)
      - Bigelow, Grace. 2 letters; 1928-1929., (7)
      - Bjørnson, Lina. 1 letter; 1928., (8)
      - Blake, Irving Hill, 1888-. 1 letter; 1927., (9)
      - Briggs, William Harlowe. 2 letters; 1928., (10)
      - Brincklé, Gertrude. 1 letter; 1929., (11)
      - Brown, Alice, 1857-1948. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (12)
      - Brown, Lucy Page. 2 letters; 1923-1925., (13)
      - Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925. 1 letter; 1920., (14)
      - Channon, Vesta Westover. 1 letter; 1929., (15)
      - Ciocca, Anne W. Langley. 1 letter; 1925., (16)
      - Clemens, Clara. 5 letters; 1924-1925 [n.d.]., (17)
      - Councilman, William Thomas, 1854-1933. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (18)
      - Cuddy, E.J. 1 letter; 1925., (19)
      - Dawes, Anna Laurens, 1851-. 1 letter; 1920., (20)
      - Day, Wilhelmina. 2 letters; 1924-1926., (21)
      - Dennis, Lorraine Durand. 1 letter; 1925., (22)
      - Dodd, Frank C. 1 letter; 1924., (23)
      - Dodge, Fanny Pryor. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (24)
      - Egan, Maurice Francis, 1852-1924. 1 letter; 1920., (25)
      - Firkins, Oscar W., 1864-1932. 2 letters; 1921-1928., (26)
      - Ford, James Lauren, 1854-1928. 3 letters; 1922 [n.d.]., (27)
      - Fuller, Henry Blake, 1857-1929. 3 letters; 1921-1929., (28)
      - Gardiner, Robert Hallowell. 1 letter; 1927., (29)
      - Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940. 12 letters; [n.d.]., (30)
      - Gill, Wilfred Austin. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (31)
      - Glode, Jean Edith. 1 letter; 1929., (32)
      - Grant, Robert, 1852-1940. 1 letter; 1920., (33)
      - Greenslet, Ferris, 1875-1959. 3 letters; 1924-1927., (34)
      - Hale, Edward Everett, 1863-1932. 1 letter; 1927., (35)
      - Harper, Joseph Henry, 1850-. 1 letter; 1920., (36)
      - Harte, Geoffrey Bret. 1 letter; 1928., (37)
      - Hay, Clarence L. 1 letter; 1927., (38)
      - Hayes, Webb C. 1 letter; 1927., (39)
      - Herrick, Mary Langley. 1 letter; 1925., (40)
      - Herrick, Robert, 1868-1938. 2 letters; 1922-1923., (41)
      - Hibben, John Grier, 1861-1933. 1 letter; 1921., (42)
      - Higgins, C.D. 1 letter; 1928., (43)
      - Hooker, Katharine (Putnam) 1849-. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (44)
      - Howe, Mark Antony DeWolfe, 1864-1960. 3 letters; 1921-1922., (45)
      - Howells, Aurelia H. 1 letter; 1928., (46)
      - Huddy, Xenophon Pearce, 1876-. 1 letter; 1928., (47)
      - Ilsley, Samuel Marshall, 1863-. 1 letter; 1929., (47a)
      - James, Alice Howe (Gibbens). 1 letter; 1920., (48)
      - James, Henry, 1843-1916. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (49)
      - James, Henry, 1879-1947. 2 letters; 1927 [n.d.]., (50)
      - Jewett, Rutger Bleecker. 1 letter; 1925., (51)
      - Jones, Henry Arthur, 1851-1929. 1 letter; 1921., (52)
      - Jordan, Elizabeth Garver, 1867-. 2 letters; 1926-1927., (53)
      - Keel, Emily. 2 letters; 1929., (54)
      - Kester, Paul, 1870-. 3 letters; 1921., (55)
      - Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936. 2 letters; 1922-1928., (56)
      - Kirk, Ellen Warner (Olney) 1842-. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (57)
      - Lane, William Coolidge, 1859-1931. 1 letter; 1928., (58)
      - Loomis, Edward E. 3 letters; 1925-1928., (59)
      - Mabie, Jeannette T. 2 letters; 1923-1924., (60)
      - McClure, Samuel Sidney, 1857-1949. 1 letter; 1890., (61)
      - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929. 1 letter; 1926., (62)
      - Merrick, Leonard, 1864-1939. 3 letters; 1921-1922., (63)
      - Metcalf, Thomas D. 2 letters; 1925-1926., (64)
      - Miller, Thomas Condit, 1848-. 1 letter; 1928., (65)
      - M[itchell], John G[rant]. 1 letter; 1928., (66)
      - Mitchell, Langdon Elwyn, 1862-. 2 letters; 1921., (67)
      - Norris, Charles Gilman, 1881-1945. 1 letter; 1928., (68)
      - Morse, Edwin Wilson, 1855-. 1 letter; 1924., (69)
      - Newbolt, Sir Henry, 1862-1938. 1 letter; 1928., (70)
      - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908. 1 letter; 1907., (71)
      - Paine, Albert Bigelow, 1861-1937. 13 letters; 1920-1928 [n.d.]., (72)
      - Palacio Valdés, Armando, 1853-1938. 2 letters; 1922-1928., (73)
      - Perry, Thomas Sergeant, 1845-1928. 2 letters; 1921-1925., (74)
      - Phillpots, Eden, 1862-. 2 letters; 1921., (75)
      - Pickard, Greenleaf Whittier. 2 letters; 1928., (76)
      - Porter, Peggy James. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (77)
      - Putnam's (G.P.) sons, New York. 1 letter; 1926., (78)
      - Pyle, Anne (Poole). 1 letter; [n.d.]., (79)
      - Rhodes, James Ford, 1848-1927. 4 letters; 1920-1921., (80)
      - Rice, M. Gordon Pryor. 1 letter; 1925., (81)
      - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit (Carow) 1861-1948. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (82)
      - Saint-Gaudens, Homer, 1880-. 1 letter; 1928., (83)
      - Scribner, Charles, 1854-1930. 4 letters; 1925., (84)
        No. 4 signed by another hand.
      - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1872-1960. 1 letter; 1925., (85)
      - Smart, Charles Allen, 1904-. 1 letter; 1929., (86)
      - Stoddard, Elizabeth Drew (Barstow) 1823-1902. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (87)
      - Storey, Moorfield, 1845-1929. 2 letters; 1927 [n.d.]., (88)
      - Strobell, Caro (Lloyd). 1 letter; 1926., (89)
      - Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946. 2 letters; 1921-1924., (90)
      - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1877-1949. 1 letter; 1922., (91)
      - Trevelyan, Sir George Otto, bart., 1838-1928. 3 letters; 1921., (92)
      - Vonnoh, Bessie O. (Potter). 2 letters; 1925-1926., (93)
      - Walker, Mary Blair Pryor. 1 letter; 1925., (94)
      - Wells, Thomas B. 1 letter; [1920]., (95)
      - White, William Allen, 1868-1944. 1 letter; 1922., (96)
      - Whitlock, Brand, 1869-1934. 4 letters; 1922-1928., (97)
      - Whitman, Julia. 1 letter; 1929., (98)
      - Whitman, Martica Langley. 1 letter; 1925., (99)
      - Whitney, Anne, 1821-1915. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (100)
      - Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) 1857-1923. 1 letter; 1920., (101)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, pres. U.S., 1856-1924. 1 telegram; 1920., (102)
      - Wister, Owen, 1860-1938. 2 letters; 1922 [n.d.]., (103)
      - Wyatt, Edith Franklin, 1873-1958. 2 letters; 1921-1928., (104)
    - 2. Letters to Mildred Howells (gift)
      - Abbott, Charles David, 1900-. 2 letters; 1925., (105)
        *45M-531
      - Adams, Fred C. 1 letter; 1955., (106)
      - Alceis, Mary. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (107)
      - Allen, Gay Wilson, 1903-. 1 letter; 1942., (108)
        *45M-533
      - Allen, James Lane, 1849-1925. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (109)
        *45M-528
      - Allen, Philippa. 1 letter; 1930., (110)
      - Allen, William Charles, 1857-. 1 letter; 1928., (111)
      - Anderson, Ruth E. 2 letters; 1932-1933., (112)
      - Archer, Charles, 1861-. 2 letters; 1930., (113)
        No. 1 with copy of a letter from W.D. Howells to William Archer (17 Sep. 1890 ).
      - Arms, George Warren, 1912-. 3 letters; 1938-1943., (114)
      - Ashley, Frederick William, 1863-1942. 1 letter; 1928., (115)
      - Authors' League of America 2 letters; 1931., (116)
        *45M-534
      - Aycock, John L. 2 letters; 1929-1936., (117)
        2: *45M-534
      - Ayer, Dana S. 4 letters; 1921-1923., (118)
        Each with two typed copies.
        *44M-122
        1TS: *59M-261
      - Bacon, Russell M. 1 letter; 1937., (119)
      - Bailey, Carolyn Sherwin, 1875-. 3 letters; 1924-1945., (120)
        No. 1 with a letter from William H. Briggs to Carolyn Sherwin Bailey.
        1-2: *45M-531
      - Baird, Rowland E. 1 letter; 1929., (121)
      - Baird, Theodore. 1 letter; 1930., (122)
      - Baker, Grace A. 3 letters; 1929-1934., (123)
        2-3: *45M-534
      - Balestier, Wolcott, 1861-1891. 1 letter; 1888., (124)
        *54M-328
      - Bangs, Francis Hyde. 3 letters; 1926 [n.d.]., (125)
      - Barrow, Hollie M. 1 letter; 1942., (126)
      - Barus, Annie H. 1 letter; 1924., (127)
      - Bates, Herbert, 1868-1929. 1 letter; 1925., (128)
      - Baxter, Sylvester, 1850-1927. 2 letters; 1920-1926., (129)
        1: *54M-328
        2: *54M-329
      - Beard, Charles Austin, 1874-1948. 3 letters; 1942., (130)
      - Belcher, Hannah Graham. 2 letters; 1943., (131)
      - Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950. 3 letters; 1922 [n.d.]., (132)
      - Bennett, Paul A., 1897-. 3 letters; 1939., (133)
      - Bewley, Luther B. 2 letters; 1937-1938., (134)
        Countersigned by G.R. Mañalac.
      - Bier, Margaret. 1 letter; 1935., (135)
      - Bigelow, Grace. 1 letter; 1929., (136)
      - Bilba, Queenie M. 1 letter; 1941., (137)
      - Bingham, H.H. 1 letter; 1941., (138)
      - Bird, Esther Brock. 1 letter; 1924., (139)
      - Bishop, William Henry, 1847-1928. 1 letter; 1921., (140)
      - Blake, Elizabeth Jessup. 2 letters; 1920., (141)
        *54M-531